Guide to the Edwin Richard Weinerman Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
In the beginning of 1970, Weinerman and his wife began a tour to survey health care in Israel, New Zealand, and Japan. This section contains an assortment of reprints, pamphlets, books, and other material that Weinerman used to prepare for his uncompleted survey trip.
The third series, MEDICAL, POLITICAL, AND SOCIAL ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS, contains both material relating specifically to Weinerman's career as a physician interested in social medicine and material reflecting his broader political and social concerns.
This series contains a wide variety of material issued by medical and public health organizations. These include the Alameda-Contra Costa Medical Association, the American Public Health Association, the Group Health Association of America, the Physicians Forum, and many others. This material, though varying from organization to organization, consists mainly of announcements, appeals, notices, and reports. There are also many newsletters, pamphlets, and other publications. Some correspondence, originally filed with this section, has been removed and filed in the CORRESPONDENCE series. This has been noted in the affected sections.
Of particular interest are papers dealing with the founding of the Medical Care Section of the American Public Health Association. There are also papers relating to the development of the Group Health Association of America from its predecessors, the Cooperative Health Federation of America, the Group Health Federation of America, and the American Labor Health Association. In addition, there are papers on the Physician's Forum, Physicians for Social Responsibility, the
Medical Committee for Human Rights and other organizations that reflect Weinerman's concern with the political and social aspects of medicine.
Other material in this series reflects this concern in a broader context. Weinerman was involved in many activities and organizations besides those that related directly to his medical career. For example, Weinerman was a prime mover in the East Bay Committee for American Activities and the East Bay Community Forum that opposed the House Committee on Un-American Activities. This series contains pamphlets, letters, and statements by those organizations as well as numerous articles, advertisements, and newspaper clippings about the House Committee and McCarthyism.
Weinerman was also involved in organizations like the East Bay Physicians' Committee for Civil Liberties and the Federation for the Repeal of the Levering Act that organized against attempts to impose political tests as a condition for medical licensure or employment. This series also contains articles, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets on the loyalty oath controversy at the University of California in the early 1950s.
Also included in this third series is material on Weinerman's work with the California Democratic Council developing issues and platforms.
Another major concern of Weinerman's was nuclear weapons and radiation hazards. Weinerman was well informed on this subject, and worked to alert the public to the dangers of nuclear testing and fallout. This series contains an extensive file of articles, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets on this subject. Weinerman was also concerned about air pollution and smog. Series III contains material on these topics also.
The fourth series, ADDRESSES AND WRITINGS, consists of articles, papers, addresses, and talks that span Weinerman's career from his days as a medical student to his untimely death.
The series is arranged alphabetically by title of address or writing. Although the material varies from title to title it includes notes, early drafts, revisions, tearsheets, abstracts, and reprints. Some newspaper clippings and press releases are also filed with some titles. Additional material on some of the articles in this series is filed in Series II, CONSULTATIONS, PROJECTS, AND PROFESSIONAL ASSIGNMENTS. When this is so, it has been noted on the appropriate folder.
Some correspondence was originally filed with the addresses and writings in this series. This has been removed and placed in the CORRESPONDENCE series. This has been noted in the affected Sections.
Scripts for broadcasts made by Weinerman on health care topics over radio station KPFA, Berkeley, California and some articles on health care topics, evidently written by Weinerman for a union oriented press service, are filed at the end of the series. There is also an article on national health insurance by Weinerman's wife entitled, "The Pains of a New Idea."
The fifth series, PERSONAL PAPERS AND MISCELLANEOUS, contains a variety of biographical materials about Weinerman including an autobiographical sketch, curricula vitae, magazine and newspaper clippings, and photographs. This series also includes letters, papers, and other documents relating to Weinerman's medical licensure, his military service and his private medical practice. The series also includes many of Weinerman's travel expense reports and vouchers from his frequent travels. There are also numerous miscellaneous bills, invoices, and receipts.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, consultations, surveys, writings, printed material, and other papers of Edwin Richard Weinerman. Material primarily reflects Weinerman's interest in public health and deals with his activities both as a consultant and administrator with various public and private health careorganizations, including the U. S. Public Health Service, Permanente Health Plan, American Public Health Association, and the Yale-New Haven Hospital. A significant part of the collection also relates to Weinerman's social and political activities, especially his concern over dangers of air pollution, nuclear warfare and radiation poisoning, and his opposition to the House Committee on Un-American Activities and the Levering Act which required loyalty oaths as a condition for medical licensure. The papers also include notebooks and course papers from his own studies at Harvard and New York University (1945-1948) as well as teaching materials from the University of California. His professional program is documented in grant applications (1963-1972), two speeches and letters written in preparation for his trip abroad in 1970, collected works (articles), and curriculum vitae. Also in the papers are letters of condolence and a transcript and audio tapes of the memorial service at Yale University following his death in 1970. These papers form part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series: I. Correspondence, 1945-1970. II. Consultations, Projects, and Professional Assignments, 1943-1970. III. Medical, Political, and Social Activities and Organizations. IV. Addresses and Writings, 1939-1940, 1942, 1945-1946, 1948-1969, n.d. V. Personal Papers and Miscellaneous.
Air -- Pollution; Working class -- Medical care; Medicine -- United States; Public health; Radiation -- Physiological effect; Radicalism; Educators; Health-officers; Physicians; Labor movement -- Medical care; Labor -- Medical care; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Aaron, Harold, 1904-; Abrams, Herbert Kerman, 1913-; Acheson, Roy M., 1921-2003; Alexander, Franz, 1891-1964; Altman, Isidore; Alwater, Reginald Myers, 1892-1957; Anderson, Odin W. (Odin Waldemar), 1914-2003; Axelrod, Solomon J. (Solomon Jacob), 1912-1987; Baehr, George, 1887-1978; Baldwin, John F., 1915-1966; Banks, A. Leslie (Arthur Leslie); Barger, A. Clifford, 1917-1996; Barnes, Asa, 1904-; Beard, Rodney Ray, 1911-; Becker, Harry J., 1909-; Bellen, Lowell; Blumgart, Herrman L. (Herrman Ludwig), 1895-1977; Boas, Ernst P. (Ernst Philip), 1891-1955; Brand, Morris; Breslow, Lester; Brewster, Agnes Wharton, 1908-; Brindle, James; Brown, Edmund G. (Edmund Gerald), 1905-1996; Brown, Esther Lucile, 1898-; Brown, Howard Juniah, 1924-; Brum, John M.; Butler, Allan Macy, 1894-; Cammer, Leonard, 1913-; Carstens, Arthur; Cherkasky, Martin, 1911-1997; Chernin, Milton, 1910-; Clark, Dean Alexander, 1905-; Clark, Tom C. (Tom Campbell), 1899-1977; Cobb, W. Montague (William Montague), 1904-1990; Cohelan, Jeffery, 1914-1999; Cohen, Wilbur J. (Wilbur Joseph), 1913-1987; Commoner, Barry, 1917-2012; Cornely, Paul B. (Paul Bertau), 1906-; Crew, F. A. E. (Francis Albert Eley), 1888-1973; Daily, Edwin; Daley, Richard J., 1902-1976; Davis, Michael M. (Michael Marks), 1879-1971; Dearing, Warren Palmer, 1905-1994; Deutsch, Albert, 1905-1961; Dodd, Thomas J. (Thomas Joseph), 1907-1971; Donabedian, Avedis; Dublin, Thomas David, 1912-; Ebert, Robert Higgins, 1914-; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Emerson, Haven, 1874-1957; Engle, Clair, 1911-1964; Epstein, Frederick Merton; Esselstyn, Caldwell B., 1902-1975; Evang, Karl, 1902-1981; Ewing, Oscar R. (Oscar Ross), 1889-1980; Falk, I. S. (Isidore Sydney), 1899-1984; Felton, Jean Spencer, 1911-2003; Fishbein, Morris, 1889-1976; Gebhard, Bruno Frederic, 1901-; Getting, Vlado Andrew, 1910-; Giamo, Robert Nicholas, 1919-; Glaser, Robert J., 1918-; Goldmann, Franz; Goldstein, Avram Shalom, 1919-; Goldstein, George; Goldwater, Leonard J. (Leonard John), 1903-1992; Grant, John B. (John Black), 1890-1962; Greenberg, Sidney Matthew; Hiscock, Ira V. (Ira Vaughan), 1892-; Holman, Halsted, 1925-; Hubbard, John P. (John Perry), 1903-; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978; Ingelfinger, Franz J. (Franz Josef), 1910-1980; James, George, 1915-; James, John Y., 1919-; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973; Jordan, Edwin Pratt, 1902-; Keene, Clifford H. (Clifford Henry), 1910-; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963; Kerr, Lorin E., 1909-; Kramer, Nathan A.; Kuchel, Thomas Henry, 1910-; Lane, Robert Porter, 1891-1951; Lear, Walter J. (Walter Jay), 1923-; Leavell, Hugh Rodman, 1902-1976; Lee, Philip R. (Philip Randolph), 1924-; Lee, Sidney S., 1921-; Lifton, Robert Jay, 1926-; Lippard, Vernon W., 1905-; Maffly, Alfred Emil, 1897-; Marine, Gene; Mathias, Charles McC. (Charles McCurdy), 1922-2010; McKeown, Tom D. (Tom Deitz), 1878-1951; McNell, John Osborne; McWilliams, Carey, 1905-1980; Means, James Howard, 1885-1967; Miller, George P. (George Paul), 1891-1982; Mott, Frederick D. (Frederick Dodge), 1904-; Muench, Hugo; Muller, Jonas Norman, 1920-1969; Murray, James E. (James Edward), 1876-1961; Myers, J. Arthur (Jay Arthur), 1888-1978; Notkin, Herbert; O'Brien, Henry R. (Henry Rust), 1891-1970; Pauling, Linus, 1901-1994; Payne, Anthony Monck-Mason, 1911-1970; Percy, Charles H., 1919-2011; Perrott, George St. J. (George St. John), 1893-1980; Peters, John P. (John Punnett), 1887-1955; Peterson, Osler Luther, 1912-; Proger, Samuel Herschel, 1906-; Rabeau, Edwin Stuart, 1920-; Rabinowitch, Eugene, 1901-1973; Reader, George G.; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970; Ribicoff, Abraham, 1910-1998; Richards, Richard, 1916-; Roberts, Dean Winn, 1914-; Roemer, Milton Irwin, 1916-2001; Rogers, Edward Saunders, 1905-; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Rosen, George, 1910-1977; Salinger, Pierre, 1925-2004; Sand, René, 1877-1953; Sheps, Cecil G. (Cecil George), 1913-2004; Sigerist, Henry E. (Henry Ernest), 1891-1957; Silver, George A., 1913-; Sinai, Nathan, 1894-1977; Smyth, Francis Scott, 1895-; Snoke, Albert W. (Albert Waldo), 1907-; Stamler, Jeremiah, 1919-; Stare, Fredrick J. (Fredrick John), 1910-2002; Stern, Bernhard Joseph, 1894-1956; Terris, Milton, 1915-; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Trussell, Ray Elbert, 1914-; Warren, Stafford L. (Stafford Leak), 1896-1981; Weinerman, Edwin Richard, 1917-1970; Wertham, Fredric, 1895-1981; White, Kerr Lachlan, 1917-; Wilinsky, Charles Francis, 1882-; Wilson, Glenn; Winslow, C.-E. A. (Charles-Edward Amory), 1877-1957; Woodcock, Leonard, 1911-; Yedidia, Avram, 1911-; United States. Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government (1947-1949); United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities; United States. Farm Security Administration; United States. Public Health Service; American Labor Health Association; American Public Health Association. Subcommittee on Medical Care; Community Health Foundation (Cleveland, Ohio); East Bay Committee for American Activities; Group Health Association of America; Group Health Federation of America; Hawaiian Sugar and Pineapple Workers' Union; International Longshoreman's and Warehouseman's Union; Miners' Memorial Hospital Association; Permanente Health Plan; United Mine Workers of America; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Medicine; Yale-New Haven Hospital
- Correspondence, 1945-1970; Series I; 8.5 linear feet (21 boxes)
  Scope and Contents note
  The CORRESPONDENCE series is arranged alphabetically by author or organization. Cross-references have been made where appropriate. In addition to the material in this series, some correspondence is also filed in the second series, CONSULTATIONS, PROJECTS, AND PROFESSIONAL ASSIGNMENTS. The authors of this correspondence are included in the following alphabetical list with a cross-reference directing the researcher to the proper section of the second series. Please note that the number in parenthesis indicates the number of items in the corresponding folder.
  Approximately 5% of the correspondence has been restricted. This is relatively minor correspondence relating mostly to job inquiries and offers, and references and recommendations. It is in a separate unnumbered box, and it is closed to research until 1995.
  - A (13), 1947, 1949, 1952, 1959, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aaron, Harold (33), 1947, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aaron, Harold (39), 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aaron, Harold (37), 1956-1958, 1960-1963, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abbott, Constance (4), 1946, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Abbott Research Laboratories (3), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Abrahamsen, David (2), 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abrams, Estelle (2), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abrams, Herbert Kerman (19), 1947-1948, 1950, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Abrams, Herbert Kerman (19), 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Abrams, Herbert Kerman (32), 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Abrams, Herbert Kerman (19), 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Abrams, Herbert Kerman (26), 1961-1965, 1967-1968, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Abramson, Judith, 1954 (1) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Acheson, Roy M. (2), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Acker, Murray S. (7), 1960, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ackerman, James and Mildred (2), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Adams, Sherman
    General note
    See: box 6, folder 223
  - Adler, Sigmund (4), 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Agnew, R. Gordon
    See: box 13, folder 542
  - Alameda-Contra Costa Medical Association (18), 1948-1951, 1956, 1958, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alameda-Contra Costa Medical Association, Public Health Committee Radiation Subcommittee (7), 1959, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alameda-Contra Costa Nurses' Workshop (5), 1956, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Alameda County Heart Association (5), 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - A1ameda County Medical Institutions (3), 1960, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alderman, Michael H. (2), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alexander, Franz (3), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Allen, John French (2), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Allison, Theodore (2), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Alpert, Joan (4), 1955 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Alter, Joseph D. (3), 1962, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Altman, Isidore (5), 1964-1965, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Altman, Isidore
    See: box 37, folder 216
  - Altschule, Mark D. (2), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Alway, Robert Hamilton (2), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Association of Medical Clinics
    See: box 10, folder 414 box 17, folder 770
  - American Board of Preventive Medicine and Public Health (14), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Broadcasting Company (1), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Cancer Society (2), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (3), 1953, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Druggist (2), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (7), 1956, 1958, 1960-1962, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Heart Association
    See: box 16, folder 699
  - American Hospital Association (6), 1953, 1961, 1964, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Hospital Supply Corporation (2), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - American Institute of Cooperation (2), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee (2), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Journal of Medical Sciences (1), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Journal of Medicine (2), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Journal Of Public Health (37), 1947, 1949-1951, 1956, 1958, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - American Journal of Public Health (26), 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Journal of Public Health
    See: box 29, folder 87
  - American Labor Health Association
    See: box 1, folders 7-8 box 3, folder 94 box 8, folder 322 box 8, folder 330 box 17, folder 750
  - American Medical Association (11), 1948-1949, 1960, 1963, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Medical Association Archives of Environmentals Health (12), 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Journal of the American Medical Association (12), 1948-1950, 1961, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - The Journal of the American Medical Association
  - American Motors Corporation
    See: box 37, folder 211
  - American Patients Association (10), 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - American Public Health Association (22), 1948-1951, 1955, 1960, 1962-1965, 1967, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - American Public Health Association, Western Branch (11), 1949, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - American Public Welfare Association (2), 1948, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - American Russian Institute
    See: box 15, folder 679
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation
    See: box 7, folder 264
  - American Trust Company (4), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - American Veterans Committee (4), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Amsel, Zili (2), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Anderson, Dewey
    See: box 15, folder 648
  - Anderson, Elin L. (4), 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Elin Anderson Memorial (5), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Anderson, Odin W. (12), 1950, 1955, 1961, 1963-1964, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Applewhite, Harold L. (3), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Armstrong, Barbara (1), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Arnold, Harry Loren
  - Arons, Milton (1), 1958 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Arts, Sciences, and Professions Council (3), 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Ashkenazy, Moses (2), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Asia, Benjamin S. (7), 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Associated Cooperatives (5), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges (6), 1948, 1950, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Association of Internes and Medical Students (4), 1946, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Association for Nursery Education (3), 1957 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Association of Western Hospitals (3), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Atwater, John (2), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Atwater, Reginald Myers (10), 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Aull, John (1), 1956 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Avnet, Helen Hershfield (3), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Axelrod, Joseph (1), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Axelrod, Solomon Jacob (29), 1946, 1948-1949, 1951-1952, 1956, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Axelrod, Solomon Jacob (19), 1960-1964, 1968, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Azulay, Abraham (1), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - B (32), 1947 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Backer, K. H. (3), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Badgley, Robin F. (1), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Baehr, George (21), 1948-1951, 1963, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Baird, Dugald (1), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Baisden, Richard N. (8), 1953, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Baldwin, John Finley, Jr. (10), 1955, 1958-1959, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Bamberger, Lee (8), 1955, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Bancroft, Richard A. (9), 1955-1956, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Banks, Arthur Leslie (13), 1949-1951, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Bard, Marc (2), 1968, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Barger, A. Clifford (5), 1949, 1952-1953, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Barnes, Asa (3), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Barnes, Asa
    See: box 34, folder 171
  - Barnes, Hubert J. (2), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Barron, Howard L. (1), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Baskin, Arnold (1), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Baugartner, Leona (1), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Bauhofer, F. A. (2), 1968 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Bazell, A. H. (1), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Beale, John P. (1), 1961 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Beall, Hayes
    See: box 8, folder 322
  - Beard, Rodney Rau (7), 1951, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Becker, Harry J. (11), 1948, 1951-1952, 1965-1967, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Beckjord, Philip R. (2), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Beeson, Paul B. (9), 1962-1963, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Beeston, John (4), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Behrens, John (2), 1956 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - The Bellaire Medical Group
    See: box 14, folder 612
  - Bellen, Lowell (3), 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Belloc, Nedra B. (2), 1950,1952 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Beloff, Jerome
    See: box 9, folder 376
  - Bender, Bernard (2), 1955 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Benison, Saul (2), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Berek, Seymour (1), 1954 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Berg, C. van den (2), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Berger, Edward J. (7), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Berke, Mark (4), 1954, 1956, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Berkeley Area Jewish Community Center (2), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Berkeley, City of (4) (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Berkeley Gazette (1), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Berkeley Jewish Senior Citizens (2), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Berkeley Mental Health Association (4), 1950, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Berman, Herman (2), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Betcher, Charles (2), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Better Homes and Gardens (4), 1947 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Bierman, Pearl (1), 1957 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Bird, Bedford W. (3), 1947, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Birkenfeld, Egon (1), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Bjorndahl, Madelynn (2), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Black, Francis L. (1), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Blackman, A. C. (1), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Blanchard, Leland B. (2), 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Blaney, Roger (2), 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Bliss, A. Harry (1), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Block, James (1), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Bloomberg, Allan Ellia (5), 1957, 1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Bloomfield, Arthur L. (2), 1951, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Bloomfield, Samuel (8), 1956, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Blue Cross (6), 1948-1949, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Blue Shield (1), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Blumgart, Herrman Ludwig (35), 1946-1947, 1950-1953, 1956, 1958-1959, 1962, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Boas, Ernst Philip (12), 1947-1949, 1953, undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Ernst P. Boas Memorial Fund (16), 1955-1960, 1963, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Boelter, Llewellyn Michael Kraus (3), 1950 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Bond, Douglas Danford (3), 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Bondy, Philip Kramer (6), 1965, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Bonnet, Henri (1), 1951 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Bonnevie, Paul
  - Borhani, Nemat Ollah (4), 1962, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Boucot, Katharine R.
    See: box 1, folder 33
  - Boudin, Leonard B. (3), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Bower, Anthony (2), 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Bowman, William M. (4), 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Boynoff, Morris (1), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Brackett, Charles E. (2), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Brackett, Elizabeth W. (1), 1950 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Brand, Morris (35), 1950, 1952, 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Brand, Morris (15), 1959-1960, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 95)